Christopher Glinka

Jr. Software Developer

Contact

Edmonton, AB (587) 778 8210 glinkachris@gmail.com

Profiles

Portfolio: <u>cglinkadesigns.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>Christopher Glinka</u>

GitHub: CGlinka95

Key Skills

Communication
Team Leadership
Mentoring
Project Management
HTML
CSS
JavaScript
React
Bootstrap
MUI
Flutter/Dart.js
C#
.NET Core
Linq
SQL
Python

Summary

Aspiring and enthusiastic Software Developer with 3 years of technical education at NAIT's DMIT program, looking for opportunities related to software development. A natural team player that can also flourish in a team leadership role. Known for his charisma, reliability, flexibility, adaptability, consistency, and ability to effectively delegate tasks and problem-solve on the spot.

Experience

October 2021 - Present

Director of Education • Code Ninjas, St. Albert & Windermere

Teaching children ages 6-15 about coding concepts based on an evolving curriculum, starting with block coding, transitioning to JavaScript and eventually Lua, C#, and Unity game engine.

- Assisted on the Code Ninjas Windermere team that was recently awarded the Black Belt Center 2022 award for being in the top 5% of the company.
- Leadership role on the Code Ninjas, St. Albert team that broke more company-wide records for a single location's grand opening. 70+ student sign-ups prior to opening day, then breaking-even and surpassing 120 active accounts within 3 months of operation.
- Successfully constructed and taught multiple curriculums for various summer camps, including Web Development, beginner and intermediate Roblox Studio development, Lego robotics, and 3D modelling and printing.
- Awarded the St. Albert center's 'Got Yo' Back' award for always going above and beyond my direct responsibilities, being willing to lend a helping hand, having consistent reliability, and attending additional events and fundraisers to help the company grow and give back to the community.

July 2021 – November 2021 Barista • Starbucks, Namao, Edmonton

January 2014 – March 2020 Senior Sales Associate & Key-holder • GameStop, St. Albert

Education

September 2020 – Present

DMIT • Northern Alberta Institute of Technology

Studying in the Computer Software Development stream.

- Dean's Honor Roll 2021 & 2022
- Worked on a team of 3 other software developers to create a mock web application for a motorcycle shop's backend system from the ground up. We used the .NET Core framework with C# to build the backend business logic that stores, retrieves, and updates data from the database with an intuitive and accessible frontend UI/UX. The project can be viewed on my GitHub profile under eBike-WebApp.

September 2016 – April 2020
Bachelor of Arts • Concordia University of Edmonton
Graduated with a Major in English and a Minor in Psychology.

 Excelled in group research projects that present data and important information in an accessible and concise manner, both written and presentation format.

References

Dan Mouris • NAIT Instructor

Email: dmouris@nait.ca

Shannon Stevenson • Director of Operations and Owner of Code

Ninjas St. Albert & Windermere

Phone: (825) 440 5485

Email: shannon.stevenson@codeninjas.com

Annabelle Syms • Director of Customer Service at Code Ninjas

Windermere

Phone: (780) 236 1536

Email: annabelle.syms@gmail.com